<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<module configVersion="1.2">

	<!-- Module Properties -->
	<id>${project.parent.artifactId}</id>
	<name>${project.parent.name}</name>
	<version>${project.parent.version}</version>
	<package>org.openmrs.module.chartsearchai</package>
	<author>OpenMRS</author>
	<description>${project.parent.description}</description>
	<updateURL>https://modules.openmrs.org/modules/download/${project.parent.artifactId}/update.rdf</updateURL>
	<require_version>${openmrsPlatformVersion}</require_version>

	<require_modules>
		<require_module version="2.44.0">org.openmrs.module.webservices.rest</require_module>
	</require_modules>

	<aware_of_modules>
		<aware_of_module>org.openmrs.module.querystore</aware_of_module>
	</aware_of_modules>

	<!-- Module Activator -->
	<activator>org.openmrs.module.chartsearchai.ChartSearchAiModuleActivator</activator>

	<!-- Hibernate Mappings -->
	<mappingFiles>
		ChartEmbedding.hbm.xml
		ChartSearchAuditLog.hbm.xml
	</mappingFiles>

	<!-- Privileges -->
	<privilege>
		<name>AI Query Patient Data</name>
		<description>Allows querying patient charts using the AI-powered chart search</description>
	</privilege>

	<privilege>
		<name>View AI Audit Logs</name>
		<description>Allows viewing the audit log of AI chart search queries</description>
	</privilege>

	<privilege>
		<name>Manage AI Index</name>
		<description>Allows triggering a full reindex of all patients into the AI chart search retrieval backend</description>
	</privilege>

	<!-- Global Properties -->
	<globalProperty>
		<property>chartsearchai.llm.engine</property>
		<defaultValue>local</defaultValue>
		<description>LLM inference engine. "local" (default) runs a GGUF model on the host via a bundled llama-server subprocess on the loopback interface — no external network calls, data stays on the server. "remote" calls an OpenAI-compatible chat completions API over the network — requires chartsearchai.llm.remote.endpointUrl, chartsearchai.llm.remote.apikey, and chartsearchai.llm.remote.modelName to be configured. Use "remote" for self-hosted GPU inference servers (vLLM, Ollama, text-generation-inference) or cloud-hosted models (OpenAI, Anthropic, Google AI).</description>
	</globalProperty>

	<globalProperty>
		<property>chartsearchai.llm.remote.endpointUrl</property>
		<defaultValue></defaultValue>
		<description>URL of the OpenAI-compatible chat completions endpoint. Required when chartsearchai.llm.engine is "remote". Examples: http://localhost:11434/v1/chat/completions (Ollama), http://gpu-server:8000/v1/chat/completions (vLLM), https://api.openai.com/v1/chat/completions (OpenAI), https://api.anthropic.com/v1/chat/completions (Anthropic), https://generativelanguage.googleapis.com/v1beta/openai/chat/completions (Google AI), https://openrouter.ai/api/v1/chat/completions (OpenRouter).</description>
	</globalProperty>

	<globalProperty>
		<property>chartsearchai.llm.remote.modelName</property>
		<defaultValue></defaultValue>
		<description>Model name to request from the remote LLM endpoint. Required when chartsearchai.llm.engine is "remote". Examples: llama3.3 (Ollama), meta-llama/Llama-3.3-8B-Instruct (vLLM), gpt-4o (OpenAI), claude-opus-4-7 (Anthropic), gemini-2.5-pro (Google AI), anthropic/claude-opus-4.7 (OpenRouter).</description>
	</globalProperty>

	<globalProperty>
		<property>chartsearchai.llm.modelFilePath</property>
		<defaultValue>chartsearchai/gemma-4-E4B-it-Q4_K_M.gguf</defaultValue>
		<description>Relative path, including the filename, within the OpenMRS application data directory to the GGUF LLM model file used for inference. Example: chartsearchai/gemma-4-E4B-it-Q4_K_M.gguf (resolves to &lt;application-data-directory&gt;/chartsearchai/gemma-4-E4B-it-Q4_K_M.gguf). The recommended model is Gemma 4 E4B Instruct (Q4_K_M quantization, ~5GB). Download from https://huggingface.co/unsloth/gemma-4-E4B-it-GGUF. Path traversal (e.g. "..") is not allowed.</description>
	</globalProperty>

	<globalProperty>
		<property>chartsearchai.embedding.preFilter</property>
		<defaultValue>false</defaultValue>
		<description>When true, uses embedding similarity to pre-filter patient records to the most relevant ones before sending to the LLM. Embeddings are indexed on first patient access and kept up to date automatically. Set to true to enable embedding-based filtering. Default: false — the LLM needs the full chart for negative reasoning ("there are no records of X"), which a similarity pre-filter cannot reliably support.</description>
	</globalProperty>

	<globalProperty>
		<property>chartsearchai.retrieval.pipeline</property>
		<defaultValue>embedding</defaultValue>
		<description>Selects the retrieval pipeline used to pre-filter patient records before sending them to the LLM. Options: "embedding" (default) uses vector similarity via an ONNX model with custom scoring; "lucene" uses Apache Lucene BM25 text search; "hybrid" combines Lucene BM25 and embedding kNN search using Reciprocal Rank Fusion (RRF) — same quality as the Elasticsearch pipeline but with no external services required; "elasticsearch" uses Elasticsearch hybrid search combining BM25 text and kNN vector search via RRF (requires Elasticsearch 8.14+ configured in OpenMRS). All require chartsearchai.embedding.preFilter to be true. Records are indexed automatically on first access. Changing this setting takes effect on the next query.</description>
	</globalProperty>

	<globalProperty>
		<property>chartsearchai.llm.systemPrompt</property>
		<defaultValue></defaultValue>
		<description>Custom system prompt sent to the LLM before patient records and the question. If empty (the default), the module uses its built-in prompt — which is iterated on alongside the rest of the pipeline and is what the eval suite tests against. Set this only to override the built-in default for this deployment (e.g. to adjust tone, citation format, or add site-specific guidance).</description>
	</globalProperty>

	<globalProperty>
		<property>chartsearchai.llm.timeoutSeconds</property>
		<defaultValue>300</defaultValue>
		<description>Maximum number of seconds to wait for the LLM to generate a response before timing out. Default 300s gives cold queries (model load + full-chart prefill + generation) headroom on CPU-only deployments. On GPU or remote-API setups, lower values are reasonable.</description>
	</globalProperty>

	<globalProperty>
		<property>chartsearchai.llm.idleTimeoutMinutes</property>
		<defaultValue>30</defaultValue>
		<description>Minutes of inactivity after which the local llama-server process is stopped to free RAM. The server is automatically restarted on the next query. Set to 0 to keep it running indefinitely. Only applies when chartsearchai.llm.engine is "local".</description>
	</globalProperty>

	<globalProperty>
		<property>chartsearchai.llm.serverPort</property>
		<defaultValue>18085</defaultValue>
		<description>Port number for the embedded llama-server when chartsearchai.llm.engine is "local". Change if the default port conflicts with another service.</description>
	</globalProperty>

	<globalProperty>
		<property>chartsearchai.llm.contextSize</property>
		<defaultValue>32768</defaultValue>
		<description>Context window size in tokens for the embedded llama-server (local engine only). The full system prompt + serialized chart + question must fit within this. Larger values let bigger charts pass through full-chart mode but increase the KV cache memory footprint roughly linearly. Default 32768. Increase if you see "Patient chart exceeds the LLM context window" errors and have headroom for a larger KV cache; reduce on memory-constrained hardware. Only applies when chartsearchai.llm.engine is "local".</description>
	</globalProperty>

	<globalProperty>
		<property>chartsearchai.rateLimitPerMinute</property>
		<defaultValue>10</defaultValue>
		<description>Maximum number of AI chart search queries a single user can make per minute. Set to 0 to disable rate limiting.</description>
	</globalProperty>

	<globalProperty>
		<property>chartsearchai.auditLogRetentionDays</property>
		<defaultValue>90</defaultValue>
		<description>Number of days to retain AI chart search audit log entries. Entries older than this are automatically purged by a daily scheduled task. Set to 0 to disable purging and retain all logs indefinitely.</description>
	</globalProperty>

	<globalProperty>
		<property>chartsearchai.cacheTtlMinutes</property>
		<defaultValue>0</defaultValue>
		<description>Number of minutes to cache AI chart search responses for identical patient and question combinations. Avoids redundant LLM calls. Set to 0 to disable caching (default).</description>
	</globalProperty>

	<globalProperty>
		<property>chartsearchai.warmupEnabled</property>
		<defaultValue>true</defaultValue>
		<description>When true (default), opening a patient chart triggers a background warmup that primes the LLM prompt cache (system prompt + serialized chart) so the first AI query on that patient skips full prefill cost. The warmup serializes the chart and sends an empty-query prefill request to the local llama-server. Has no effect when chartsearchai.llm.engine is "remote" (remote providers manage their own caching) or when chartsearchai.embedding.preFilter is true (the prompt prefix varies per query, so a chart-only warmup cannot be reused). Set to false to disable.</description>
	</globalProperty>

	<globalProperty>
		<property>chartsearchai.embedding.topK</property>
		<defaultValue>10</defaultValue>
		<description>Maximum number of records to retrieve via embedding similarity when pre-filtering is enabled. Lower values produce more focused LLM responses; higher values provide more context but may reduce reasoning quality. Default: 10.</description>
	</globalProperty>

	<globalProperty>
		<property>chartsearchai.querystore.enabled</property>
		<defaultValue>false</defaultValue>
		<description>Master switch for the querystore-backed retrieval path. When true, chartsearchai delegates retrieval to openmrs-module-querystore — getPatientChart when chartsearchai.embedding.preFilter is false (the recommended shape for full-chart LLM reasoning), or searchByPatient with top-K when preFilter is true — and bypasses chartsearchai's own embedding pipelines. Requires the querystore module to be installed; if absent, the flag-on path degrades to an empty chart. Also suppresses chartsearchai's AOP indexing and the EmbeddingIndexTask backfill to avoid double-indexing. Default: false. NOTE — flipping this from false to true does not refresh pre-existing Lucene/Elasticsearch/MySQL embedding indices, which then stop receiving updates; flipping back exposes a stale snapshot. Treat the off→on transition as one-way for any deployment that previously ran the embedding pipelines, or re-run EmbeddingIndexTask after disabling. See chartsearchai.querystore.topK for the result cap.</description>
	</globalProperty>

	<globalProperty>
		<property>chartsearchai.querystore.topK</property>
		<defaultValue>30</defaultValue>
		<description>Number of top results to request from the querystore when chartsearchai.querystore.enabled is true. Separate from chartsearchai.embedding.topK so the querystore path can be tuned independently of the legacy pipelines. Default: 30.</description>
	</globalProperty>

	<globalProperty>
		<property>chartsearchai.embedding.similarityRatio</property>
		<defaultValue>0.80</defaultValue>
		<description>Minimum similarity score as a fraction of the top result's score. Records scoring below this ratio are excluded even if within the topK limit. For example, 0.80 means a record must have at least 80% of the best match's similarity score. Lower values include more records; higher values are more selective. Must be between 0 and 1. Default: 0.80.</description>
	</globalProperty>

	<globalProperty>
		<property>chartsearchai.embedding.scoreGapMultiplier</property>
		<defaultValue>2.5</defaultValue>
		<description>Controls adaptive topK by detecting natural cluster boundaries in similarity scores. When the gap between consecutive scores exceeds this multiplier times the running average gap, the cluster boundary is found and lower-scoring records are excluded. Higher values (e.g. 3.0) are more permissive (include more records); lower values (e.g. 2.0) are more aggressive at cutting. Set to a very large value (e.g. 999) to effectively disable gap detection and rely solely on the similarity ratio threshold. Default: 2.5.</description>
	</globalProperty>

	<globalProperty>
		<property>chartsearchai.embedding.keywordWeight</property>
		<defaultValue>0.3</defaultValue>
		<description>Additive keyword bonus weight in the hybrid retrieval formula: finalScore = semanticScore + weight * keywordScore. Keyword overlap can only increase the score, never decrease it. Set to 0 to disable keyword matching. Default: 0.3.</description>
	</globalProperty>

	<globalProperty>
		<property>chartsearchai.embedding.typeBoostFactor</property>
		<defaultValue>1.0</defaultValue>
		<description>Score multiplier applied to records whose resource type matches the query intent (e.g., drug orders when the query is about medications). Set to 1.0 to disable type boosting (default). Values like 1.2-1.5 provide moderate boosting. Must be between 1.0 and 3.0. Default: 1.0.</description>
	</globalProperty>

	<globalProperty>
		<property>chartsearchai.embedding.queryPrefix</property>
		<defaultValue></defaultValue>
		<description>Prefix prepended to the user query before embedding. Leave empty for models like all-MiniLM-L6-v2 that were not trained with instruction prefixes. Set to "search_query: " or "Represent this sentence for searching relevant passages: " for models that support instruction-aware queries (e.g., BGE). Default: empty.</description>
	</globalProperty>

	<globalProperty>
		<property>chartsearchai.embedding.maxSequenceLength</property>
		<defaultValue>256</defaultValue>
		<description>Maximum WordPiece token sequence length for embedding input. Increase when using models that support longer contexts (e.g., 512 for BGE models). Must be between 32 and 8192. Default: 256.</description>
	</globalProperty>

	<globalProperty>
		<property>chartsearchai.embedding.minScoreGap</property>
		<defaultValue>0.10</defaultValue>
		<description>Minimum absolute gap between consecutive similarity scores required for the adaptive cutoff detector to trigger. Prevents premature cutting when a relatively large gap (compared to a tight cluster's running average) is still small in absolute terms. Only applies when gap detection is active via chartsearchai.embedding.scoreGapMultiplier. Default: 0.10.</description>
	</globalProperty>

	<globalProperty>
		<property>chartsearchai.embedding.gapValidationCosineThreshold</property>
		<defaultValue>0.47</defaultValue>
		<description>Cosine similarity threshold for validating whether a gap in the score distribution is intra-topic (e.g. different vital sign types in the same broad category) or inter-topic (a real relevance boundary). When the average cosine between records just above and below the gap meets or exceeds this threshold, the gap is considered intra-topic and the second-pass cut is skipped. Lower values are more permissive (more gaps treated as intra-topic); higher values are more aggressive at cutting. Must be between 0 and 1. Default: 0.47.</description>
	</globalProperty>

	<globalProperty>
		<property>chartsearchai.embedding.modelFilePath</property>
		<defaultValue>chartsearchai/model.onnx</defaultValue>
		<description>Relative path, including the filename, within the OpenMRS application data directory to the ONNX embedding model file. Required when embedding pre-filtering is enabled (chartsearchai.embedding.preFilter is true (non-default)). Example: chartsearchai/all-MiniLM-L6-v2.onnx (resolves to &lt;application-data-directory&gt;/chartsearchai/all-MiniLM-L6-v2.onnx). Download the model.onnx file from https://huggingface.co/sentence-transformers/all-MiniLM-L6-v2 and rename it. Path traversal (e.g. "..") is not allowed.</description>
	</globalProperty>

	<globalProperty>
		<property>chartsearchai.embedding.queryModelFilePath</property>
		<defaultValue></defaultValue>
		<description>Optional: path to a separate query-encoder ONNX model for dual-encoder architectures (e.g. MedCPT). When set, queries are embedded with this model while records use the standard model (chartsearchai.embedding.modelFilePath). When empty, the standard model is used for both queries and records (single-encoder mode). Example for MedCPT: chartsearchai/MedCPT/Query-Encoder/model.onnx</description>
	</globalProperty>

	<globalProperty>
		<property>chartsearchai.embedding.vocabFilePath</property>
		<defaultValue>chartsearchai/vocab.txt</defaultValue>
		<description>Relative path, including the filename, within the OpenMRS application data directory to the WordPiece vocabulary file (vocab.txt) for the ONNX embedding model. Required when embedding pre-filtering is enabled (chartsearchai.embedding.preFilter is true (non-default)). Example: chartsearchai/vocab.txt (resolves to &lt;application-data-directory&gt;/chartsearchai/vocab.txt). Download vocab.txt from the same model repository as the ONNX model (e.g. https://huggingface.co/sentence-transformers/all-MiniLM-L6-v2). Path traversal (e.g. "..") is not allowed.</description>
	</globalProperty>

	<!-- AOP -->
	<advice>
		<point>org.openmrs.api.EncounterService</point>
		<class>org.openmrs.module.chartsearchai.api.EncounterIndexingAdvice</class>
	</advice>

	<advice>
		<point>org.openmrs.api.ObsService</point>
		<class>org.openmrs.module.chartsearchai.api.ObsIndexingAdvice</class>
	</advice>

	<advice>
		<point>org.openmrs.api.ConditionService</point>
		<class>org.openmrs.module.chartsearchai.api.PatientDataIndexingAdvice</class>
	</advice>

	<advice>
		<point>org.openmrs.api.DiagnosisService</point>
		<class>org.openmrs.module.chartsearchai.api.PatientDataIndexingAdvice</class>
	</advice>

	<advice>
		<point>org.openmrs.api.PatientService</point>
		<class>org.openmrs.module.chartsearchai.api.PatientDataIndexingAdvice</class>
	</advice>

	<advice>
		<point>org.openmrs.api.OrderService</point>
		<class>org.openmrs.module.chartsearchai.api.PatientDataIndexingAdvice</class>
	</advice>

	<advice>
		<point>org.openmrs.api.ProgramWorkflowService</point>
		<class>org.openmrs.module.chartsearchai.api.PatientDataIndexingAdvice</class>
	</advice>

	<advice>
		<point>org.openmrs.api.MedicationDispenseService</point>
		<class>org.openmrs.module.chartsearchai.api.PatientDataIndexingAdvice</class>
	</advice>

	<!-- Internationalization -->
	<messages>
		<lang>en</lang>
		<file>messages.properties</file>
	</messages>

</module>
